<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sara A. Stoudt</title>
    <link>https://sastoudt.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Sara A. Stoudt</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2016 22:55:05 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://sastoudt.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://sastoudt.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2016 22:55:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sastoudt.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>My name is Sara Stoudt. I am a fifth year student in the UC Berkeley Statistics Department and a Berkeley Institute for Data Science Fellow. Prior to being a BIDS Fellow, I was supported by a National Physical Sciences Consortium Fellowship  with the National Institute of Standards and Technology  and part of the Data Science for the 21st Century: Environment and Society Training Program .
My research focus is on ecological applications of statistics, and I am advised by Will Fithian and Perry de Valpine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CV</title>
      <link>https://sastoudt.github.io/cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2016 22:55:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sastoudt.github.io/cv/</guid>
      <description>You can download a full copy of my CV here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coding Projects</title>
      <link>https://sastoudt.github.io/coding/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2016 22:55:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sastoudt.github.io/coding/</guid>
      <description>Miscellaneous Coding Projects  Census Data Aggregator: While at the Los Angeles Times Data Desk, I worked to add functionality to the Census data aggregator, an open source Python library that helps aggregate data from the census while still accounting for margin of error. stringr Vignette: I wrote a vignette to help users transition from performing string operations in base R to using the tidyverse stringr package.
Wealth Tax Shiny App: UC Berkeley economists Emmanuel Saez and Gabriel Zucman analyzed Senator Elizabeth Warren’s proposal for a wealth tax, and Fernando Hoces de la Guardia from the Berkeley Initiative for Transparency in the Social Sciences (BITSS) wanted to turn their work into an open policy analysis (OPA).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research</title>
      <link>https://sastoudt.github.io/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2016 22:55:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sastoudt.github.io/research/</guid>
      <description>Graduate Research (ongoing) Clarifying the Identifiability Controversy in Species Distribution Modeling  Advisors: Will Fithian and Perry de Valpine  Ecologists commonly make strong parametric assumptions when formulating statistical models. Such assumptions have sparked repeated debates in the literature about statistical identifiability of species distribution and abundance models, among others. At issue is whether the assumption of a particular parametric form serves to impose artificial statistical identifiability that should not be relied upon or instead whether such an assumption is part and parcel of statistical modeling.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching</title>
      <link>https://sastoudt.github.io/teaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2016 22:55:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sastoudt.github.io/teaching/</guid>
      <description>You can download a draft (work in progress) of my teaching statement here. 
Spring 2018

Graduate Student Instructor with Professor Deb Nolan

STAT 198- Blogging for Data Science

Students write 4 posts during the semester related to mathematics, statistics, computer science, and/or data science. Two blog posts can be about anything related to mathematics, statistics, computer science, or data science and are brainstormed using Andrew Gelman’s diary activity  Two blog posts are more technical: a vignette style blog post and a data analysis focused blog post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing</title>
      <link>https://sastoudt.github.io/writing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2016 22:55:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sastoudt.github.io/writing/</guid>
      <description>Links to my writing that lives somewhere other than my blog.  Blogging Beyond: based on Deb Nolan and my experience teaching writing for statistics and data science, a belated response to @KelseyAHE’s request for a blog about student blogs

Gender Issues Roundtable Discussion: A Case Study in Uncomfortable Conversations: with Kellie Ottoboni, Rebecca Barter, and Ryan Giordano

Fixed, Mixed, and Random Effects as part of Rebecca Barter&amp;rsquo;s Practical Statistics group</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>